There is only one rule in love:
bring happiness to those you love.
Stendhal, "Journal, 19 June 1805"
This is amazing, Ayanokoji-sensei.
Kiyotaka-kun is an unquestioned genius.
Being born a genius means nothing.
Don't forget, the purpose
of this organization
is to produce excellence from
even the most inferior DNA.
R-Right.
Don't show bias to him
just because he's my son.
Even if that means it breaks him.
You surprise me, Arisu.
You don't usually take so
much interest in things.
Experiments to create artificial genius...
It's only natural that I'm curious.
You never change, do you?
That boy...
Oh, that's Sensei's son.
His name, I believe...
is Ayanokoji Kiyotaka-kun.
Ayanokoji Kiyotaka...
We will now begin this
year's final special exam.
Each class, choose five of the presented
ten subjects, and press "confirm."
Final Special Exam
English
I've been waiting for the day we'd do battle.
I'm sure it was destiny that made it happen.
English
Modern Lit
Math
Mental Math
Destiny, huh?
That's a very abstract concept.
Well, I am a young maiden.
After all that effort to
make it up to Class C,
he has to face Sakayanagi-san...
Poor Ayanokoji-kun.
I can't help but sympathize.
Just see that you remain impartial.
Sorry!
Well, then.
Let's determine the first subject.
Normally, I'd ask that
you take it easy on me...
But I hope you'll give it
everything you have.
Round 1
Intentionally keeping your ace,
Sudo-kun, in reserve?
The captains' rule for this round
lets us swap in one participant
at the moment of our choosing...
Captains' Special Rule
Ability to swap out one member at chosen time.
I see.
They're doing pretty great for
not having Sudo-kun in there.
It's strange.
This seems far too easy.
I'm invoking the captains' rule.
Swapping members.
Great work.
Sudo Ken swaps in for Hondo Ryotaro.
Give it your best!
I should have known that simple
strategy wouldn't fool you.
Just as I want it.
What's wrong?
Left completely helpless
against an amateur like me?
Damn it... You've played
basketball before, huh?
You were going easy on us before!
No. You just suck that bad.
Screw you!
The smallest of psychological blows
will cause Sudo-kun to crumble.
No matter how superlative one's
skills, if the mind is weak...
Weak?
When did you get your information on that?
Your team lost the lead after
you came out, basketball club.
Like hell! I'll show you!
So simple-minded.
Kanji!
Oh?
Yeah!
We can still turn it around!
That's our Sudo!
Hey, looking cool!
Onodera-san, nice shot!
We've still got time!
Ike and Sudo are in total sync, huh?
The winner: Class C!
Hell yeah!
We did it, guys!
I see.
You're suggesting he's matured, as well?
Awesome!
Great job, everyone!
How surprising.
We beat Class A!
Final Special Exam
3x3 Basketball
Although...
We've played a powerful
card in Sudo-kun early on.
Match two, typing battle.
Round 2
Typing Battle
Another of Class C's chosen subjects?
It appears you have the luck of the draw.
Round Two: Typing
Sotomura Hideo Class C
Final Special Exam Round Two
Typing Battle
Class A Yoshida Kenta
Round 3: English Test
Class C Entrants:
Inogashira, Shinohara, Sato, Karuizawa
Round 4: Math Test
Class C Entrants:
Yukimura, Hirata, Wang, Kushida
Round 5: Archery
Class C Entrant:
Miyake
Quite impressive.
Just one more!
Final Special Exam
3x3 Basketball
Typing
English
Math
Archery
Yes! We're almost there!
We're winning all the subjects we submitted!
Which means...
If we get a good pull on the next subject...
The next competition will be...
Round 6
Mental Math
It's one of theirs?
Oh, no...
Choose the students to participate.
I suppose I can't afford to lose this one.
Our participants will be Tamiya Emi-san
Tamiya Emi
and Katsuragi Kohei-kun.
Okay!
I'll go with Matsushita Chiaki
Matsushita Chiaki
Koenji Rokusuke
and Koenji Rokusuke.
I see. Because the rule is that the
winner isn't decided by combined score,
Round 6: Mental Math
but by the single student
with the highest score.
The plan is that even if Koenji-kun
doesn't take it seriously,
Matsushita-san is there to cover him.
There will be ten questions in all.
The further you go, the harder they will
become, but the more they will be worth.
Begin!
Final Special Exam Round 6
Question 1
Huh? What the...
Hang on, that's impossible!
All of those?!
There's not enough time!
I couldn't remember them all.
That damn Koenji...
He's not taking it seriously at all!
Koenji-kun...
End
That was all ten questions.
Pencils down.
Did they not even try to
solve those last ones?
The captains' rule is that the captain
may answer one question themselves.
I'll answer question 10.
Select question to answer.
Please enter your answer.
What about you, Ayanokoji-kun?
Select question to answer.
I'll do the same.
Please enter your answer.
I've never tried it before, but it's
quite an amusing little pastime.
The answer to the last question
is 7,619, isn't it?
Well, well.
Please enter your answer.
Isn't that a surprise?
I will now announce the results.
The top placer is Katsuragi Kohei.
1st: Katsuragi Kohei
2nd: Matsushita Chiaki
3rd: Tamiya Emi
4th: Koenji Rokusuke
The winner is Class A.
Guess it's no use.
Damn it!
Koenji-kun...
I told Katsuragi-kun in advance...
that if he betrayed us, I'd have a
hard-working Class A student expelled.
Final Special Exam Round 6
Mental Math
Matsushita Chiaki
Koenji Rokusuke
Katsuragi Kohei
Tamiya Emi
I'm glad Koenji-kun didn't take it seriously.
When you don't have control
over a kind of power,
you can't integrate it into your strategy.
Indeed.
Still, it's three against three now.
You caught up to us,
but you don't seem happy.
Because after this last subject,
our fun time together will end.
That just leaves...
I will now announce the
seventh and final subject.
Round 7
Chess
To think this would be the
final subject chosen...
Captains' Special Rule
The captain can freely give instructions to the
player for up to 30 minutes of the allotted time.
A rule that gives the captains a
lot of time to give instructions...
Which means the battle will
be between the two of us.
I'm sorry to tell you, chess is my specialty.
Well, well.
What a happy coincidence.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
He's the most excellent subject here.
But I can't help but pity the boy.
Why?
He's been in this facility
since the moment of his birth.
He's never once experienced
the love of a parent or the
warmth of a human touch.
Captain A
Final Special Exam Round 7
Chess
Horikita Suzune
Hashimoto Masayoshi
Let us now begin the final round.
I only learned chess a few months ago,
so please take it easy on me.
I'm in the same boat.
I only started a week ago.
No one can beat me when I'm not holding back.
Ayanokoji Kiyotaka
I wonder why...
I feel like I'll win this.
Pretty twisted attack, right?
Did Sakayanagi-san teach it to you?
Seems like you learned from
someone pretty skilled, too.
You'll just have to speculate.
Well, that's fine.
Although... mind if I
ask you about Ayanokoji?
Since the island test, I've been wondering
if he might be the real mastermind.
What makes you think that?
Just instinct.
Could you give me an answer?
Give you an answer?
I don't have the slightest idea
what you're talking about.
Oh, really?
You seem a little flustered to me.
I'd anticipated that you
might try to shake me.
But that won't be enough to
break through my stronghold.
Are you sure you can afford
to spend this time talking?
Now it's getting interesting.
The endgame seems sadly
predictable at this rate.
I suppose it's time I got involved.
I'd like to say I'm still in this,
but I'm actually pretty grateful.
Is the gap in our abilities this wide?
Captain C
Not going to step in, Ayanokoji-kun?
I suppose I'll have no choice
but to go on and win.
I'm not strong enough for this.
Ayanokoji-kun!
I suppose it's time.
In accordance with the
special rule, Class C's captain
has joined.
At last, we'll be able to compete.
Horikita Suzune
Captain C
Hashimoto Masayoshi
Captain A
Hey, you guys.
Just how fast do you think?
Our battle must appear rather pathetic.
Agreed.
What do you think, Ayanokoji-kun?
Has my playstyle touched your heart?
Yes, painfully so.
If I made a single mistake,
you'd overwhelm me.
I'm not worried.
I know you won't make even
the smallest of mistakes.
You could give up if you wanted to, then.
I'm afraid I can't do that.
If you won't make a mistake,
I'll just have to crush
you with pure ability.
Oh, I'm having so much fun.
I'm sure this won't be enough to end you.
Wait, that move...
Listen, Arisu.
If the children here grow
up into superior specimens,
and facilities like these become commonplace,
I think that will be the
beginning of something awful.
Don't worry.
I will stop that from happening.
You really are brilliant, Ayanokoji-kun.
I had a lot of fun with you.
It really is a shame to end it.
But...
This will be the end.
Ayanokoji-kun.
I don't want to lose.
I...
I don't want to admit defeat.
I want to win!
I can't do it.
I can't figure out how to beat Sakayanagi.
You're the only one who can!
This move...
That was brilliant, Ayanokoji-kun.
There's no doubt in my mind that an ordinary
person couldn't make a play like that.
However...
I have a reason why I need to win, as well.
Genius must be something you're born with.
As the heir to truly superior DNA,
I will prove that facilities
like that one are meaningless.
That is the salvation that I must provide.
And... there's something
that I must show you.
Check.
I forfeit.
That's it.
The winner is Class A.
It was a fine match.
It could have gone either way at any time.
But...
What?
That last move... Did you really make it
because you thought it would be ideal?
Why else would I?
You're a cruel person, Ayanokoji-kun.
You could just be honest with her.
About what?
You normally would have been
the one to win that match.
The move he made then was
even better than the one
that would have been considered ideal.
Are you saying... you interfered in our test?
You altered Ayanokoji-kun's command to
change the one Horikita-san received?
Why didn't you admit to it?
You really think he'd reveal
things he didn't have to?
It's all your fault, you know.
Because you gave Ayanokoji-kun
that ridiculous protection point.
However... pathetic though it is,
a victory is a victory.
Why not celebrate it?
You're skilled at provocation.
You will pay a high price for this.
A child like you?
That's an interesting claim.
You're free to try what you like.
Just as expected, Ayanokoji-kun.
I lose.
You accepted that very readily.
I lost in a replay of the same conditions.
I'm satisfied with that result.
For this special exam,
you could have submitted only one-on-one
matches to ensure that we fought.
Why didn't you?
I wanted to avoid your abilities
becoming publicly known.
Consideration for me, then?
I'm glad I got to fight you.
I now have the answer I was seeking.
You are a true genius.
You're not simply pretending at all.
You saw me in the White Room, then?
I began to play chess after that,
hoping I'd get to face you someday.
I desperately wanted to know more about you.
Like a childhood friend who pined after
you for years, yet never found you.
Allow me to apologize for one thing.
Apologize?
I told you the reason I wanted
to avoid a one-on-one,
but that was a lie.
The truth is...
I wanted to be in the same space
as you for as long as I could.
People learn warmth through contact.
That's a very important thing.
There's nothing wrong with
the warmth of human contact.
Do remember that.
What do you mean by that?
That's a message from me,
delivered later than I meant it.
Now, let's head home.